<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, musings and geekiness</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com/</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Powering down Google Reader</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I’ve tried to trim down my subscriptions I’m still a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;ww.google.com/reader&quot; title=&quot;Google Reader&quot;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; and it’s a shame that they’re pulling the plug on it. I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feedly.com/home&quot;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; earlier today and it seems to do the job fairly well. The iOS app is beautiful too but I’m not completely sold on the whole magazine-like interface. The intergration with other web services is pretty amazing though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>March 14, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/03/14/powering-down-google-reader</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A modern web designer's workflow</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A really nice talk from Mr. &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/&quot; title=&quot;CSS-Tricks&quot;&gt;CSS-Tricks&lt;/a&gt; himself, Chris Coyier. Bring some Coke and make some popcorn, because the video clocks in at 1 hour and 43 minutes. Impressive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>March 11, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/03/11/a-modern-web-designers-workflow</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A brand new blog</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve yet again redesigned the layout of this site and this time it’s a hell of a lot different. I grew tired of the old look since it in all honestly looked boring and decided to give it some colors. I found the typeface &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Roboto&quot; title=&quot;Roboto&quot;&gt;Roboto&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago and I like it so much that I decided to use it, which was the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hey-what-is-that-theme&quot;&gt;Hey, what is THAT theme?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahfrederick.com/&quot; title=&quot;Noah Fredrick&quot;&gt;Noah Frederick’s&lt;/a&gt; beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahfrederick.com/blog/2011/lion-terminal-theme-peppermint/&quot; title=&quot;Peppermint terminal thehe&quot;&gt;Peppermint theme&lt;/a&gt; for the OS X’s terminal. I remember stumbling onto his &lt;a href=&quot;http://noahfrederick.com/vim-color-scheme-hemisu/&quot; title=&quot;Hemisu&quot;&gt;Hemisu colorscheme&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; and for some reason I also found Peppermint. I even liked it so much that I hacked together a Vim colorscheme for it that I use quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sass--compass--3&quot;&gt;Sass + Compass = &amp;lt;3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sass&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://compass-style.org/&quot; title=&quot;Compass&quot;&gt;Compass&lt;/a&gt; exclusively for the CSS writing. I’ve been wanting to use it for a long time and I even tried to convert the old design’s CSS to it, but I gave up pretty quickly. This time I didn’t and I of course used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/smallwork&quot; title=&quot;Smallwork&quot;&gt;Smallwork&lt;/a&gt; as a base which made the process a lot more easier and faster. Redesigning this site was also one of the things that made me re-write Smallwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;using Compass with Jekyll is also relatively easy by the way. I first tried out a couple of plugins, but I decided to implement it in my Rake task instead. While the plugins worked great it really bugged me that I couldn’t decide when to use &lt;code&gt;compass compile&lt;/code&gt; and when to use &lt;code&gt;compass watch&lt;/code&gt;. All I had to do was to add this to my &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; task in my &lt;code&gt;Rakefile&lt;/code&gt;, before &lt;code&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt; is run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;system &quot;cd assets/ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; compass compile &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd ../&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple and effective!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;funish-trivia&quot;&gt;Fun(ish) trivia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started the redesign on March 1st and I’ve made a total of 28 commits&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130309-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130309-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to the git repository I used for the development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I “skipped” support for Internet Explorer 8 in favor of using &lt;code&gt;[class^=&quot;column-&quot;]:last-child&lt;/code&gt; to remove the &lt;code&gt;margin-right&lt;/code&gt; on the grid system&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130309-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130309-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also found a pretty cool Sass function called &lt;code&gt;darken()&lt;/code&gt;, which made it easy finding a good background color for my &lt;code&gt;code&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; tags and the subtle text shadow. All of the color functions for Sass are pretty cool, in fact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pink line at the bottom of the site uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mystrd.at/modern-clean-css-sticky-footer/&quot; title=&quot;Modern Clean CSS Sticky Footer&quot;&gt;“James Dean Sticky Footer”&lt;/a&gt; approach, which is a nice little hack. I love the name too!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I tried to change as little as possible when I did the CSS for the media queries. I pratically just changed the font size and some margins. That’s it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130309-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m an obsessive commiter.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130309-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130309-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I doubt that that will cause any problems. I don’t think I know anyone that actually use Internet Explorer.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130309-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>March  9, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/03/09/a-brand-new-blog</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Re-releasing Smallwork</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in January I wrote a small paragraph about my SCSS “framework” &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/smallwork&quot; title=&quot;Smallwork&quot;&gt;Smallwork&lt;/a&gt;. When I released it I was really happy about it, but I soon realized that I’d been perhaps a bit too trigger happy with it. This weekend I decided on a whim to nuke it and start over and yesterday I re-released it. It’s pratically re-written from the ground up and it’s even smaller in size than it was before. I cleaned up the code like a maid and threw out quite a bit of extra “baggage” that I was probably never going to use anyway. Now I feel like it actually could be useful to someone else too, which is really nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created yet another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; plugin, this time just a simple wrapper for &lt;a href=&quot;http://compass-style.org/&quot; title=&quot;Compass&quot;&gt;Compass&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;em&gt;Smallwork&lt;/em&gt; is built with. I was getting sick of having to type either &lt;code&gt;:!compass compile&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:sh&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code&gt;compass compile&lt;/code&gt; so I threw together a really basic function that makes it much easier. Now I only have to type &lt;code&gt;:CompassCompile&lt;/code&gt;. Another nice feature is that you don’t actually have to close the command prompt&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130305-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130305-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which means that you can use &lt;code&gt;:CompassWatch&lt;/code&gt; without it interfering with Vim&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130305-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130305-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If all goes well I think I’ll even publish it on the official Vim scripts website too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130305-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Normally you can’t do anything until you’ve exited the command prompt and hit &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;, but a simple solution from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://vim.wikia.com/wiki/Execute_external_programs_asynchronously_under_Windows&quot; title=&quot;Execute external programs asynchronously under Windows&quot;&gt;Vim Wiki&lt;/a&gt; fixed that.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130305-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130305-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Atleast on Windows. I don’t think that there’s an easy way to do that on Unix, which is unfortunate.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130305-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>March  5, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/03/05/re-releasing-smallwork</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Fixing Jekyll's encoding shenanings</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After installing the 0.12.1 version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; I started to get an annoying error that the encoding was wrong. I’m really picky about saving all my files as &lt;code&gt;UTF-8&lt;/code&gt;, so I couldn’t for the life of me figuring out why it all of a sudden threw that kind of error. I even reinstalled 0.12.0 and sure enough, that version worked without a problem. The solution is to set the default language and encoding before running Jekyll, ie. &lt;code&gt;set LANG=en_EN.UTF-8&lt;/code&gt; for Windows or &lt;code&gt;export LANG=en_EN.UTF-8&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130303-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130303-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for Unix. Since I’m a lazy person I of course implemented it in my &lt;code&gt;Rakefile&lt;/code&gt;, similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;require &#39;rbconfig&#39;

LANG = en_EN.UTF-8

if RbConfig::CONFIG[&quot;host_os&quot;] =~ /mswin|mingw/
  SET = &quot;set&quot;
else
  SET = &quot;export&quot;
end

task :build do
  system &quot;#{SET} LANG=#{LANG} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; jekyll&quot;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;RbConfig&lt;/code&gt; part is actually a neat trick I found a couple of weeks ago. It apparently works better than using &lt;code&gt;RUBY_PLATFORM&lt;/code&gt; since it picks up the actual OS rather than the Ruby platform.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130303-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130303-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I’m not sure that the &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt; part is really necessary but it doesn’t hurt either. You can of course just create an alias too if you’re only using Unix, ie: &lt;code&gt;alias jekyll=&quot;export LANG=en_EN.UTF-8 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; jekyll&quot;&lt;/code&gt; or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130303-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I actually set my language to &lt;code&gt;sv_SV.UTF-8&lt;/code&gt;, but I figured that using the english version in an example is better.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130303-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130303-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;RUBY_PLATFORM&lt;/code&gt; when you’re working with other Ruby implementations such as JRuby doesn’t quite work, if I understand it correctly.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130303-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>March  3, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/03/03/fixing-jekylls-encoding-shenanings</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>
