<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Themes For FocusWriter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;By being bored and wanting to have something to do I made a couple of themes for &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; based on other editors like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iawriter.com/&quot; title=&quot;iA Writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bywordapp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Byword&quot;&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt; and color schemes like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized&quot; title=&quot;Solarized&quot;&gt;Solarized&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out some screenshots of them by either clicking on this post's title &lt;em&gt;(I finally get the chance to use an external link!)&lt;/em&gt; or right &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/focuswriter-themes/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter Themes&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you'd rather want that. They're also available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/focuswriter-themes&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter Themes on GitHub&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 15, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/15/themes-for-focuswriter</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>My New Writing App</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Up until now I've mostly written all of my posts and pages in a program called &lt;a href=&quot;http://markdownpad.com/&quot; title=&quot;MarkdownPad&quot;&gt;MarkdownPad&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I really like it I sometimes feel that it's a bit too... clunky, for lack of a better word. It's great for doing shorter writings and editing files, but I haven't really been comfortable using it as a long form writing environment. As I do with a lot of stuff I once again sat down in front of my screen to find something new and preferably awesome that I could use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter&quot;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt; is a cross platform, distraction-free text editor &lt;em&gt;(or writing environment, as the developer himself calls it)&lt;/em&gt;. It's a pretty neat looking app with an minimalistic interface but it also has suprisingly many features. It supports both rich text and plain text formatting, but sadly there's no real &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; support, meaning that it doesn't have any syntax support. You can still write it in the editor of course though and it can actually both open and save documents with a &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; file extension, which is good. What I mostly like about is that it has a clean interface and that it hides all the menus by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-14-focuswriter.png' title='FocusWriter' alt='FocusWriter'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I really hate about distraction-free/full screen editors is that I often feel too trapped when I use them. I mean, they're probably a life saver for many people but it''s not my cup of tea. If I'm stuck I want to be able to take a quick break and then jump right back in when I get the urge to write some more. Fortunately, &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; gives me the ability to do so. You can also make your own themes where you can change the colors, the typeface and the margins for the writing area which also comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I've only been using it for about two or three days, but I have a feeling that it'll stick around for a much longer period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A side note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my suprise I first found an app for &lt;em&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(who would've thought?)&lt;/em&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;http://uberwriter.wolfvollprecht.de/&quot; title=&quot;UberWriter&quot;&gt;UberWriter&lt;/a&gt;. It looks &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iawriter.com/&quot; title=&quot;iA Writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(apart from some minor color details)&lt;/em&gt;, which means that it's incredibly gorgeous. You should try it out if you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 14, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/14/my-new-writing-app</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>ResophNotes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most frequent mention apps I've seen around the web during the last couple of months is &lt;a href=&quot;http://notational.net/&quot; title=&quot;Notational Velocity&quot;&gt;Notational Velocity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(or rather a popular fork of it called &lt;a href=&quot;http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/&quot; title=&quot;nvALT&quot;&gt;nvALT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;. In short it's a note taking app where you can both create plain text notes and store, tag and search among them. You can also synch them synch with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dropbox.com/&quot; title=&quot;Dropbox&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(by creating a folder and storing your notes on your account)&lt;/em&gt; and a couple of other services, which enables you to access your files from pretty much anywhere as long as you have some kind of internet connection. Sadly it's only available for &lt;em&gt;Mac&lt;/em&gt; computers so I went out on my way to see if I could find an alternative. I did and it's name is &lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt;, which was originally built as a Windows based app for &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Simplenote&quot;&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt; but you can also use it with &lt;em&gt;Dropbox&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-13-resophnotes.png' title='ResophNotes' alt='ResophNotes'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's maybe not be pretty as it's &lt;em&gt;Apple&lt;/em&gt; counterparts, but the foundation is the same. It's nice to have all of your notes in the same place, and I really like that you're able to tag them. It means that I can place all of my blog post ideas in a tag called &quot;blog&quot; and so on. It also has a lot of options, meaning you can customize it to your liking. For example, I'm planning to hide all of the icons once I've learned all of the shortcuts properly since I like a more clean cut look. I've been only using it for a couple of days, but so far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 13, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/13/resophnotes</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>External Links In The Post Title</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I finally managed to add the ability to have external links in my post titles on this site. I tried and I tried, but for some reason I couldn't get it to work properly. I waited a couple of days and tried again and then boom, it worked. I don't know what I did wrong the first time, but I'm glad that it now works. Thanks to the YAML Front Matter and Liquid tags it's actually not that hard to add to your site. I don't really know if I'll use it that much, but I quite like to have that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to add the external links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following markup is a simplified version of what I use. You should modify it to your liking and preferably add alt and title tags to your links. First, add this in the front matter portion of your post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;external-link: http://www.example.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to add an external link to your title, just replace the link itself with &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; or remove the whole thing. The markup of your post title on your front page should look like something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of having the above markup, replace it with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% if post.external-link %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.external-link }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% else %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% endif %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added this in the markup for my post layout:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% if page.external-link %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ page.external-link }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ page.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% else %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;{{ page.title }}&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% endif %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you're done! I would encourage you to also add an actual permalink to your own post if you're using external links, like this for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A side note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually had to add another plugin so I could show the Liquid tags since Jekyll parses them automatically. You can find it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/1020852&quot; title=&quot;Raw tag for Jekyll&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt; over at GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 11, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/11/external-links-in-the-post-title</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Gummesson 2.0</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make the jump and thus this site now has a spanking new design. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Oswald&quot; title=&quot;Oswald&quot;&gt;Oswald&lt;/a&gt; is used for the headings and the navigation and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Asap&quot; title=&quot;Asap&quot;&gt;Asap&lt;/a&gt; is used for the body copy. I quite like them together since the former has a kind of slab-serif quality to it, even though it's actually a sans-serif. The bold and italic versions of Asap aren't perfect, but they look much better than than they did before. I haven't had the chance you check out how they look in &lt;em&gt;Firefox&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Opera&lt;/em&gt;, but I hope they look good in them too. I've also increased the font size from 112.5% &lt;em&gt;(which usually equals to 18px)&lt;/em&gt; to 125% &lt;em&gt;(20px)&lt;/em&gt; just because I'm a big fan of having a bigger size for readability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 10, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/10/gummesson-two-point-zero</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>