<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Amazing iOS 6 Maps</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I really doubt that anybody hasn't seen the above website, but it still makes me laugh like a madman. The second largest city in Sweden (Gothenburg) no longer exists and I apparently live in my neighbor's bushes, not in my actual house as I would expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 25, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/25/the-amazing-ios-6-maps</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>FocusWriter 1.4.0 Released</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A new version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter 1.4.0&quot;&gt;FocusWriter 1.4.0&lt;/a&gt; was just released yesterday. Quite a lot has changed since in the app since I was previously using 1.3.6 since it was the latest stable release. This version feels like a big step up. The biggest changes in my opinion is that you now have the option to change the line spacing in your themes and that the save dialog won't force you to either save your document as a .txt or a .rtf file, which is good news if you're writing in &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; like I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite new feature is the focus mode. The focus mode lets you chose to focus on either one line, three lines or a paragraph by &quot;blurring&quot; out the rest of the text by changing it's opacity (or something to that effect), which makes it blend in with the background and thus lets you focus on the the current focused text. This feature can also be found in &lt;em&gt;iA Writer&lt;/em&gt;, which seems to be a constant inspiration for the development of &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; by the way (I don't see that as a bad thing though), although the former only lets you focus on one sentence at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-23-focuswriter-140.png' title='Focus mode in FocusWriter 1.4.0' alt='Focus mode in FocusWriter 1.4.0'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's also a new function called &lt;em&gt;Scenes&lt;/em&gt;, but I doubt I'll use it that much since I personally don't need it form my kind of writing. It essentially lets you create markers for different scenes in your document separating them by using a couple of characters. The default detection for a new scene is two hashes (which coincidentally is a second level heading in &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt;). I could see it being handy if I'm writing a really long blog post containing lots of headings though. &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; is first and foremost made for writers, so there's definitively a use for that type of thing. All in all I still think that &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; is the best writing app I've come across.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 23, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/23/focuswriter-140-released</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Short Note About The New iOS</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The battery life on my &lt;em&gt;iPhone 4S&lt;/em&gt; has improved when I'm not using 3G or WiFi...but it's gotten worse when I'm actually using something that requires an internet connection to work. Granted I only upgraded to &lt;em&gt;iOS 6&lt;/em&gt; about two days ago, so maybe it'll get better with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One step forward and one step back, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 21, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/21/a-short-note-about-the-new-ios</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Joys Of Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After about a month of what I would say is fairly regularly blogging on this website I've come to the conclusion that I really love to write, even though I'm not sure that anybody is actually reading it. A couple of years ago I toyed with the idea to actually study to become a journalist, but that didn't plan out. In hindsight, it was probably for the best. I did get a small freelance job as a music writer and reviewer that lasted about a year, which I enjoyed even though I think I got a bit repetitive at the end of the run. My newfound love of writing is probably what keeps me going. I haven't set up an &lt;em&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/em&gt; account nor a &lt;em&gt;FeedBurner&lt;/em&gt; either, just because I realize that statistics doesn't really matter much to me. Sure, I would be really happy to know that someone appreciate my writing and what I have to say, but I'm mostly doing it for the sake of myself. It doesn't hurt that I'm probably getting better and better at it either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 20, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/20/the-joys-of-writing</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>My Adventure With Peppermint OS</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I've always been a bit of a geek, so naturally I decided to try out a lightweight &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt; distro on my old computer (mostly just for kicks). I looked around on the internet and came across a couple of distros that looked good, and in the end I decided to try out &lt;a href=&quot;http://peppermintos.com/&quot; title=&quot;Peppermint OS&quot;&gt;Peppermint OS&lt;/a&gt;. The ISO file was small enough for me to burn it onto a CD rather than a DVD, plus I was confident (well, as confident as you can be without having actually tried it) that my old computer could atleast handle it pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Peppermint OS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's an short introduction borrowed from the official website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peppermint was designed for enhanced mobility, efficiency and ease of use. While other operating systems are taking 10 minutes to load, you are already connected, communicating and getting things done. And, unlike other operating systems, Peppermint is ready to use out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though my old computer is borderline ancient, it took about 10-15 minutes at the most to install the whole thing (I did run in to some problems at first, but it think that was the computer's fault rather than the actually OS itself). The initial setup went smooth too, though it took a couple of minutes before my internet connection worked. So far I haven't been tweaking that much, but I'm defintively looking forward to doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-18-peppermint-os.png' title='Peppermint OS Three' alt='Peppermint OS Three'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that I've install a &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt; distro (I've poked around in Ubuntu a few times) and I must say that so far I'm impressed. The next step for me is to try to customize it a bit, especially the look of the shell. I'm quite excited to dive in to the (hopefully) wonderful world of &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt;. I might even get stuck in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 18, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/18/my-adventure-with-peppermint-os</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>