<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com/</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Vim: Nearly Four Weeks In</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My little &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; adventure continues and a couple of days ago I uninstalled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sublime Text 2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;. I have nothing against it and I still think it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic editor but I feel like I don&amp;rsquo;t really need it anymore. I&amp;rsquo;m no way near being a expert but like I&amp;rsquo;ve stated before I really like using Vim and I don&amp;rsquo;t see that that changing anytime soon. I&amp;rsquo;ve also configured my Vim files &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/vimfiles&quot; title=&quot;My Vim files on GitHub&quot;&gt;quite a bit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130124-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130124-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to stay away from adding too many plugins since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to rely on too many of them. Right now I use eight which I think is a reasonable number. I also finally re-did my git repository so that every plugin is a git submodule&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130123-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130123-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which makes updating them much, much easier. I have to say that the customization possibilities in Vim are extraordinary. Who knew that that would be the case for an editor that&amp;rsquo;s just slightly younger than me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-tips-and-tricks&quot;&gt;A Few Tips And Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go through my whole &lt;code&gt;vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file since it&amp;rsquo;s currently about 225 lines long &lt;em&gt;(and heavily commented)&lt;/em&gt; but I want to share a few handy settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the language to english:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;if has(&quot;unix&quot;)
  language messages C
else
  language messages en
endif  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;m strange but I tend to stick with using english as my default language in nearly every app I install. I find it to be much easier googling for help. Since I both use Linux and Windows I had to add the &lt;code&gt;if...else...endif&lt;/code&gt; part so that it plays nice with both of them&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130124-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130124-3&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that this needs to be at the very top of your &lt;code&gt;vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file if you want it to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the cursorline as a mode indicator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;au InsertEnter * set nocursorline
au InsertLeave * set cursorline
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted an easier way to quickly see which mode I was in without relying on some third party plugin. I of course have the &lt;code&gt;showmode&lt;/code&gt; setting enabled but by removing the cursorline from insert mode I don&amp;rsquo;t even have to move my eyes one bit. I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to see which line I&amp;rsquo;m on anyway when I&amp;rsquo;m actually typing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autoresize all windows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;au VimResized * :wincmd =
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resizing your windows in Vim can be a bit of a pain, especially if you want to go from using a fullscreen to something smaller or the other way around. The above setting makes it a lot less of a hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ignore certain files:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;set wildignore+=.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the features that I like the most about Sublime Text 2 and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I can use it in Vim too. If I can&amp;rsquo;t edit a certain filetype I don&amp;rsquo;t want to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130124-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One of the most useful tweaks I&amp;rsquo;ve found for writing blog posts was from Peter Provost&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://peterprovost.org/blog/2012/04/22/editing-octopress-slash-jekyll-posts-in-vim/&quot; title=&quot;Editing Octopress/Jekyll Posts in Vim&quot;&gt;Editing Octopress/Jekyll Posts in Vim&lt;/a&gt;. The YAML front matter doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like crap anymore, yay!&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130124-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130123-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Git-Tools-Submodules&quot; title=&quot;Git submodules&quot;&gt;A repository inside another repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130123-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130124-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This works for everything by the way. I think that the default name for Mac is &lt;code&gt;macunix&lt;/code&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130124-3&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 24, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/24/vim-nearly-four-weeks-in</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Serve: The Ugliest Static Site Generator In The World</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s been up with me lately but I do know that during the last couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;shipped&amp;rdquo; a lot of things. I mean, most of them are basic things but I&amp;rsquo;ve had fun while doing them. So yesterday I added yet another repo to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson&quot; title=&quot;My GitHub account&quot;&gt;my GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/serve&quot; title=&quot;Serve&quot;&gt;Serve&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Serve&lt;/em&gt; is a static site generator which focuses on generating small sites that only need to consist of a few pages at the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with an faint idea. I wanted to build something useful that could parse a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot; title=&quot;Markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; files and convert them to static HTML files. It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I absolutely adore &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, but I tend to roll with an idea once I get it. I first threw together a one file script that had the same basic functionality and went from there. My goal was to really learn how to use modules and classes since I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly shied away from them&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130120-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130120-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at a lot of different projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; but to be honest I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really comprehend everything, since I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty inexperienced when it comes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruby-lang.org/&quot; title=&quot;Ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and programming languages in general. I didn&amp;rsquo;t just want to give up though. I was going to finish my newly started projects goddamnit, even if it would take me months. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It suddenly clicked for me and I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130120-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130120-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, which is such an amazing feeling. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long for me to transform the ugly script into it&amp;rsquo;s current state. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it&amp;rsquo;s perfect but it looks a hell of a lot nicer then it did when I started and it sort of keeps me excited to continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning stuff is awesome, especially when you notice your own progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130120-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve of course read about them and have an basic understanding of their purpose but actually seeing them in action and implementing them is so much better for my learning experience.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130120-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130120-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;With &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo; I mean how to use them to get them to work with the rest of the code. &amp;ldquo;Inheritance!&amp;rdquo; was literally the thing that popped up in my head that made me understand everything. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how the brain works sometimes.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130120-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 20, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/20/serve-the-ugliest-static-site-generator-in-the-world</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Vimium: The Hacker's Browser</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably the last person on earth to discover this neat little extension but it&amp;rsquo;s nonetheless a great thing for both navigating in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/chrome&quot; title=&quot;Chrome&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and learning the basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 18, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/18/vimium</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>I Created Yet Another (Pointless) App</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My experiments with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sinatra&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; framework continues and yesterday I pushed yet another app to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heroku.com/&quot; title=&quot;Heroku&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;http://slugize.ellengummesson.com/&quot; title=&quot;Slugize&quot;&gt;Slugize&lt;/a&gt;. It only has one small purpose: creating a slug out of a blog title, which can be pretty handy when you use a static site generator like &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t decide on a title until a few seconds before I &amp;ldquo;hit publish&amp;rdquo; which means that fixing the slug is usually the last thing I do. I find it extremely annoying that I have to manually type out &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; between every word in the title and change every letter to be in downcase&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130115-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130115-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I guess you can call it lazyiness too. Now I only need to copy and paste the title into &lt;em&gt;Slugize&lt;/em&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;ll do it automatically for me and I also added an option to append the current day&amp;rsquo;s date to it. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how being lazy sometimes makes you more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130115-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I do actually use the &lt;code&gt;rake post&lt;/code&gt; function that I created for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/jekyll-rake-boilerplate&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll Rake Boilerplate&quot;&gt;Jekyll Rake Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt; project, but I only use it when I&amp;rsquo;m 100% sure on a post&amp;rsquo;s title and content.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130115-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 15, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/15/i-created-yet-another-pointless-app</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Launch Week</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finally pushed something to the master branch of a thing I started working on last week, &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; title=&quot;Smallwork&quot;&gt;Smallwork&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small yet full featured &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot; title=&quot;SCSS&quot;&gt;SCSS&lt;/a&gt; framework, or starting point as I&amp;rsquo;d like to call it. The first time I tried SCSS was way back in August or September but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it until I started learning Ruby. The code length measures in at a total of 1156 numbers of lines&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130112-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130112-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which kind of makes it my most ambitious work to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also played around with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sinatra&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; again and came up with a simple journal app which uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://datamapper.org/&quot; title=&quot;Datamapper&quot;&gt;Datamapper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sqlite.org/&quot; title=&quot;SQLite 3&quot;&gt;SQLite3&lt;/a&gt; for storing everything in a database. Like I mentioned earlier I&amp;rsquo;m quite fond of Sinatra, especially since it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to understand what do to and what&amp;rsquo;s going on. The code is so self-explanatory that I sometimes have to pinch myself to see that I&amp;rsquo;m not in fact dreaming. I&amp;rsquo;m no expert but I like where I&amp;rsquo;m going with it and I&amp;rsquo;ve barely scratched the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also thinking about extending &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramit.ellengummesson.com/&quot; title=&quot;Kramit!&quot;&gt;Kramit!&lt;/a&gt; a bit, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes&amp;hellip; I guess I should try to slow myself down a bit since I&amp;rsquo;ve launched three new projects this week alone. I&amp;rsquo;m having fun though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130112-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s including blank lines and comments. It&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty big number though. The compiled CSS code is 682 lines long and that&amp;rsquo;s without any additional content besides the basic structure itself.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130112-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 12, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/12/launch-week</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>