<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random Ramblings, Overall Geekiness And Other Musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Footnotes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I look into some simple solution to enable support for footnotes since that&amp;rsquo;s something that regular Markdown doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:121109-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:121109-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My current Markdown interpreter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtomayko/rdiscount&quot; title=&quot;rdiscount&quot;&gt;rdiscount&lt;/a&gt;, sadly doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any support for it but another one called &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramdown.rubyforge.org/&quot; title=&quot;kramdown&quot;&gt;kramdown&lt;/a&gt; do. I thought that maybe kramdown was going to be significantly slower&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:121109-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:121109-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s actually hardly noticeable. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramdown.rubyforge.org/syntax.html&quot; title=&quot;kramdown syntax&quot;&gt;syntax&lt;/a&gt; it processes the markdown a little differently but luckily I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed any changes, since I was worried for a while that I&amp;rsquo;d had to edit some posts. I did however had to add some thing in my CSS so that the footnotes didn&amp;rsquo;t look to out of place, but since the markup consists of some attribute selectors that didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out to be a big hassle either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to wrap this short post up, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a pretty fast markdown interpreter for Jekyll that has some additional features you should definitively try out kramdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:121109-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Although forks of Markdown like &lt;a href=&quot;http://michelf.ca/projects/php-markdown/extra/&quot; title=&quot;Markdown Extra&quot;&gt;Markdown Extra&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/&quot; title=&quot;MultiMarkdown&quot;&gt;MultiMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; do.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:121109-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:121109-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;kramdown is built exclusively with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruby_(programming_language)&quot; title=&quot;Ruby (Programming Language)&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; while rdiscount also uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_(programming_language)&quot; title=&quot;C (Programming Language)&quot;&gt;C&lt;/a&gt;, which to my understanding makes the whole process faster.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:121109-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>November  9, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/09/footnotes</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Pop - A Minimal Approach To Digital Notetaking</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After trying Squarespace Note for a few days I decided that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really for me. Even though I feel in love with the interface I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really get over the fact that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t choose another folder other than the app&amp;rsquo;s default to save my notes to in Dropbox. I still think it&amp;rsquo;s a very competent and useful app though, but it’s just not my cup of tea. I decided to look for something else and I did find a worthy replacement: &lt;a href=&quot;http://minimaltools.com/&quot; title=&quot;Minimal Tools - Pop&quot;&gt;Pop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pop&quot;&gt;Pop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The description from &lt;a href=&quot;http://minimaltools.com/&quot; title=&quot;Minimal Tools - Pop&quot;&gt;the official website&lt;/a&gt; describes the purpose of the app perfectly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pop is simply a convenient place for writing things down — that piece of paper you grab to write when you have an idea. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help you do anything smarter or more organized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that&amp;rsquo;s there&amp;rsquo;s no integration with any other service or app whatsoever. You&amp;rsquo;re only able to write down what you want to keep, and then select it all and copy it to another text editor for further editing and writing. I love that. Note was really similiar to my default text editor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iawriter.com/&quot; title=&quot;iA Writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;, while Pop certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t. I can only use one blank “canvas” to write down my ideas and thoughts. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing to fiddle with. That feels quite refreshing to be honest (I actually wrote the majority of this post in said app). My handwriting is incredibly messy so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have an app that can quite frankly replace my need for an actual physical notebook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2012-11-06-pop-for-ios.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pop for iOS (with a swedish keyboard)&quot; title=&quot;Pop for iOS (with a swedish keyboard)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel confident that Pop is going to prove itself useful for me. I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely certain that I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue to use it as a springboard for ideas, blog posts and just general thoughts. Just like how it&amp;rsquo;s meant to be used, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November  6, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/06/pop-a-minimal-approach-to-digital-notetaking</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Gummesson 3.0</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this you should&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the design once again has changed. I tried to made a promise to myself that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fiddle with the site&amp;rsquo;s design for a week but obviously that didn&amp;rsquo;t work out. I did find a rather stunning typeface, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Tinos&quot; title=&quot;Tinos&quot;&gt;Tinos&lt;/a&gt;, and I decided to run with it while the inspiration was high. I think that it looks so much cleaner now and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally limited my need to change things around on the site. I&amp;rsquo;m confident that this reincarnation of it will stick around much longer than the previous ones (that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard since I&amp;rsquo;ve had two different designs since the end of August this year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I really need to find a good monthly archives plugin for Jekyll though since the post count is getting too high to work with the current solution which just lists them all, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November  4, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/04/gummesson-three-point-zero</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Fiddling</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I find it a bit funny that since I posted my last blog post with my little ramble about redesigning I&amp;rsquo;ve fiddled around about ten times with different elements  on this site. Now my goal is to not do it for atleast a couple of days. That shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard I hope. I really do need to clean up the code though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November  2, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/02/fiddling</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>To Re-Redesign Or Not</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot lately about yet again redesigning this site. I&amp;rsquo;ve changed quite a few annonyances I&amp;rsquo;ve had since launching the new design back in September but I&amp;rsquo;m still not fully content with it. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s the way it is when you constantly pick up new things from other sites and blogs that you regularly go to. I have a tendency to get extremely tired at looking at the same thing for longer periods of time too. I think that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering so much with my current design. If I could I&amp;rsquo;d probably change the site every month, but that&amp;rsquo;s an impossible feat since I&amp;rsquo;m not a designer at all. I rarely get by in that department. But still I feel a need to strive for something more aesthetically pleasing. Or maybe I just care too much and should just let it be. I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 31, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/31/to-re-redesign-or-not</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>