<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Tech Support Scammer Dials Ars Technica</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This made me laugh. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October  4, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/04/a-tech-support-scammer-dials-ars-technica</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Offline</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday while I was traveling a bit by train I read Paul Miller's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/label/offline&quot; title=&quot;Paul Miller's offline series on The Verge&quot;&gt;offline series&lt;/a&gt; on The Verge about his year without internet. Admittedly I've previously only skimmed through a couple of the articles, but I decided to catch up on all of them since I had some time to kill during my ride. I think it's an intriguing idea yet at the same time a bit nightmarish. I mean, without an internet connection I wouldn't even have read the articles. I think that a lot of people around my age can all relate to living their lives in some form or another through the internet and I'd probably be bored to death if I couldn't use it at all. It might be sad, but it's true nonetheless. The feeling of not being able to have an immediate access to instant information about pretty much anything would be more than overwhelming. I don't know if I should feel bad about it either... Perhaps not, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October  3, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/03/offline</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>iA Writer - Now With Markdown Preview</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The iPhone/iPad version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/se/app/ia-writer/id392502056?mt=8&quot; title=&quot;iA Writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; (which I use) got an update just in time for the release of iOS 6, and I'm really happy about the fact that it now finally has a Markdown preview mode. I was actually looking around for another app that had a function like that, but now I think I'm going to stick around with using it (even though &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/drafts/id502385074?mt=8&quot; title=&quot;Drafts&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; looks good too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-30-ia-writer-preview.png' title='iA Writer - Preview Mode' alt='iA Writer - Preview Mode'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not that keen on how the text in the preview is formatted, but it's no the end of the world because I don't really use the app to write huge text pieces on my phone or anything like that. I think I'm good as long as I'm just using for capturing quick notes with ideas for blog posts and other writing related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 30, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/30/ia-writer-now-with-markdown-preview</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Decluttering</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the same vein as my recent RSS cleaning (mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/17/cleaning-up/&quot; title=&quot;Cleaning Up&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;) I've also started to declutter my computers from unneccassary apps, and I recently finally managed to achieve a inbox zero on my primary mail account (I've always been bad at it and I usually keep emails for way too long, but over the course of a couple of sessions I managed to get it under control by archiving a lot of emails and throwing away even more). But anways, back to the main topic of the post: decluttering your computer from stuff you don't need. When I got my new computer at the start of August I realized that I actually didn't need to install that many apps and that I mostly only had to install one per need. There are of course a few exceptions to that rule, like text editors for example, but those are often not that heavy on the system anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before I started university I got a small &lt;em&gt;Samsung NC10&lt;/em&gt; netbook as a gift. Even though it was far from a beast, it was a life saver during lectures and group projects. I've tried to keep it pretty clean and not having too many things on it, but I had to have a couple of heavier apps installed due to actually working on school projects on it. I also use it as my main machine when I was home during holidays. Now that I don't have to use it for those to primary things I decided to really clean it up and use it only for browsing and the occasional writing session. I think I had about 85% of hard drive space left when I was done, and that's including the OS. The boot time is actually quite minimal seeing as the computer is over three years old. I'm actually toying with the idea to use it more now, especially since I'm getting more more and more into writing long form posts, which I can thank the decluttering for. In that retrospect you could say that less really is more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another side note is that every app I have installed on this computer is free, which is quite awesome really. I think that I'll write more on that particular subject later.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 27, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/27/decluttering</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Amazing iOS 6 Maps</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I really doubt that anybody hasn't seen the above website, but it still makes me laugh like a madman. The second largest city in Sweden (Gothenburg) no longer exists and I apparently live in my neighbor's bushes, not in my actual house as I would expect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 25, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/25/the-amazing-ios-6-maps</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>