<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random Ramblings, Overall Geekiness And Other Musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>My Adventure With Crunchbang</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about installing a Linux distro on my thrusty but ailing netbook, a &lt;em&gt;Samsung NC10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121214-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121214-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. After some intense research via Google and countless hours of Youtube videos I found one particular distro I really liked: &lt;a href=&quot;http://crunchbang.org/&quot; title=&quot;Crunchbang Linux&quot;&gt;Crunchbang Linux&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a minimal distro but highly functional and it also looked quite nice to my eyes. It&amp;rsquo;s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot; title=&quot;Debian&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; which means that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of apps for it and the support is generally good. I decided to download the current testing version, &lt;a href=&quot;http://crunchbang.org/download/testing&quot; title=&quot;Crunchbang Linux 11 Waldorf&quot;&gt;Waldorf&lt;/a&gt;, since I&amp;rsquo;m just going to use the netbook mainly for browsing and writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the &lt;code&gt;iso&lt;/code&gt; to a USB stick and played around with for a few minutes before I hit install. I was a bit worried that I&amp;rsquo;d completely break my computer but the installation went fine. It took about 10-15 minutes and then the system was up and running. I was also prepared for some tinkering with the settings and such but everything worked right out the box, even the brightness and volume controls. Color me impressed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the installation I decided to remove a couple of apps&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121214-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121214-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; since I&amp;rsquo;m not going to use them anyway. With a couple of &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get remove&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get autoremove&lt;/code&gt; and some fiddling with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbox.org/&quot; title=&quot;Openbox&quot;&gt;Openbox&lt;/a&gt; menu it was done in a matter of minutes. The default web browser, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geticeweasel.org/&quot; title=&quot;Iceweasel&quot;&gt;Iceweasel&lt;/a&gt;, wasn&amp;rsquo;t really for me so I replaced it with &lt;a href=&quot;www.google.com/chrome/&quot; title=&quot;Chrome&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. I also change the default font in system montoring tool &lt;a href=&quot;http://conky.sourceforge.net/&quot; title=&quot;Conky&quot;&gt;Conky&lt;/a&gt; to a monospaced one. I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to change a few more things, but so far I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the default experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apps&quot;&gt;Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my goal is to keep the netbook as clean as possible there was one&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121214-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121214-3&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; additional app that I just had to install: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/p/retext/home/ReText/&quot; title=&quot;ReText&quot;&gt;ReText&lt;/a&gt;. It was the only real Markdown editor with syntax highlighting that I could find. My favorite distraction free editor &lt;a href=&quot;http://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter&quot;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt; is available but since I want to keep my app count at a minimum I decided to only install ReText. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that a Debian-compatible version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://uberwriter.wolfvollprecht.de/&quot; title=&quot;UberWriter&quot;&gt;UberWriter&lt;/a&gt; is in the works so I might switch to that once it&amp;rsquo;s out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2012-12-14-crunchbang-waldorf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crunchbang Linux (Waldorf)&quot; title=&quot;Crunchbang Linux (Waldorf)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short I really love this distro. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, light on the resources, highly customizable but at the same just works. The battery life has gone down from around 5 hours to 4.5 hours, which isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad at all. In fact I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed by that too. I wholeheartedly recommend it to people who want to make the jump to Linux but don&amp;rsquo;t want to use something more resource-heavy, like the current main version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ubuntu&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, while still maintaining an all-around functionality for most users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121214-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The system specification is as followed: 1.6 GHz, 1 GB RAM, 160 GB HDD with Windows XP (previously) installed.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121214-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121214-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abisource.com/&quot; title=&quot;Abiword&quot;&gt;Abiword&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.gnome.org/gnumeric/&quot; title=&quot;Gnumeric&quot;&gt;Gnumeric&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://goodies.xfce.org/projects/applications/xfburn&quot; title=&quot;xfburn&quot;&gt;xfburn&lt;/a&gt; and a few others.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121214-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121214-3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I also installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://dropbox.com/&quot; title=&quot;Dropbox&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; but that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a given thing. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121214-3&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>December 14, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/14/my-adventure-with-crunchbang</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Robocop(y)</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While looking for an easier way to backup and sync a couple of folders on my system I came across an awesomely named command line function called &lt;code&gt;robocopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121211-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121211-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. One of the things I use it for is to quickly backup the source of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site to a folder on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://dropbox.com/&quot; title=&quot;Dropbox&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; with a simple command like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;robocopy ~/Jekyll ~/Dropbox/Jekyll *.* /mir
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see it follows the structure of &lt;code&gt;robocopy -source -destination -file -option&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;*.*&lt;/code&gt; targets every single filetype and the &lt;code&gt;/mir&lt;/code&gt; means that everything, including the subfolders, will get mirrored. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of options for it&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121211-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121211-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, ranging from copying a single file once to actually scheduling it for repeated copying. It&amp;rsquo;s not really a syncing function per se, but it works and it&amp;rsquo;s blazingly fast. I&amp;rsquo;m not really bothered by the fact that I have to manually run it either since I don&amp;rsquo;t need to sync everytime something changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage of using Robocopy is that it&amp;rsquo;s just a lot more smoother, especially since I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten more and more comfortable using the command line for everyday tasks. I can open up the CLI from anywhere, trigger a hotstring for pasting the above snippet and just hit &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121211-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robocopy&quot; title=&quot;Robust File Copy&quot;&gt;Robust File Copy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121211-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121211-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://ss64.com/nt/robocopy.html&quot; title=&quot;SS64's Robocopy Reference&quot;&gt;an excellent summary&lt;/a&gt; from SS64. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121211-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>December 11, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/11/robocopy</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Struggles Of Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back I wrote a blog post called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2012/09/20/the-joys-of-writing/&quot; title=&quot;The Joys Of Writing&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Joys of Writing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; where I expressed my love for the craft that is writing. While I still feel the same I&amp;rsquo;ve also found it quite hard from time to time, especially during the last couple of weeks. In other words, the honeymoon period of starting this website is over. I sit down, launch &lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt;, look through my notes and find a topic I want to write about but absolutely nothing comes out. Not even a word. It&amp;rsquo;s a good old-fashioned writer&amp;rsquo;s block and I hate it. Even though I probably have a very low number of readers&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121209-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121209-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I still like to write and I feel quite powerless when I can&amp;rsquo;t do so. In short, writing keeps me sane. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize as I type this out that this blog post has a goodbye vibe written all over it, but fortunately that&amp;rsquo;s not the case. I just need to vent out some of my frustration. I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep fighting it and I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ll come out of it sooner than later. I guess that in a sense this post is already a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121209-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2012/09/20/the-joys-of-writing/&quot; title=&quot;The Joys Of Writing&quot;&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve stated before&lt;/a&gt;, I don&amp;rsquo;t use any kind of analytics on this website so I haven&amp;rsquo;t got a clue about the readership.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121209-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>December  9, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/09/the-struggles-of-writing</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Apps For Windows</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of what I consider awesome apps and utilities for Windows. Even though there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of them I sometimes find that it&amp;rsquo;s quite hard to find those gems that really stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focuswriter&quot;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter&quot;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best minimalistic writing app I&amp;rsquo;ve come across. It&amp;rsquo;s open source, cross platform and portable too. It has a lot of features but those never get in the way since it can hide a lot of them, which is something that&amp;rsquo;s great for my writing productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;markdownpad&quot;&gt;MarkdownPad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I mainly do all of my writing in FocusWriter I find it a good thing to sometimes preview my formatting in another app and that&amp;rsquo;s were &lt;a href=&quot;http://markdownpad.com/&quot; title=&quot;MarkdownPad&quot;&gt;MarkdownPad&lt;/a&gt; fits right in with it&amp;rsquo;s excellent live preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resophnotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt; is the only real dedicated note taking app for Windows with the option of saving the notes in plain text that I&amp;rsquo;ve found. By enabling a global hot key you can pretty much create a note as soon as it pops into your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;todotxtnet&quot;&gt;todotxt.net&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to almost exclusively using plain text for saving pretty much anything I do I&amp;rsquo;ve also started to use an iOS app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://todotxt.com/&quot; title=&quot;todo.txt&quot;&gt;todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;. todo.txt provides a graphical interface for a simple plain text file (called todo.txt) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://benrhughes.com/todotxt.net/&quot; title=&quot;todotxt.net&quot;&gt;todotxt.net&lt;/a&gt; is the Windows counterpart to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uv-outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uvoutliner.com/&quot; title=&quot;UV Outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/a&gt; is probably the only good single pane outliner for Windows. It can also be used as a task manager if you enable the  checkbox function, which is pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;launchy&quot;&gt;Launchy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Launchy is a free cross-platform utility designed to help you forget about your start menu, the icons on your desktop, and even your file manager. Launchy indexes the programs in your start menu and can launch your documents, project files, folders, and bookmarks with just a few keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the description from &lt;a href=&quot;http://launchy.net/&quot; title=&quot;Launchy&quot;&gt;Launchy&amp;rsquo;s official website&lt;/a&gt; is sufficient enough so I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autohotkey&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autohotkey.com/&quot; title=&quot;AutoHotKey&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt; is an fantastic little app that you can add your own scripts to. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s about creating a keyboard shortcut for an app, launching a specific document or having a lot of text expansions it can do the job for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;virtuawin&quot;&gt;VirtuaWin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://virtuawin.sourceforge.net/&quot; title=&quot;VirtuaWin&quot;&gt;VirtuaWin&lt;/a&gt; is a small for enabling up to four virtual desktops on your screen. It&amp;rsquo;s not as fancy as OS X&amp;rsquo;s Spaces and Expose or another vritual desktop app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://dexpot.de/&quot; title=&quot;Dexpot&quot;&gt;Dexpot&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s extremely lightweight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shotty&quot;&gt;Shotty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for something better than the built in snipping tool and I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://shotty.devs-on.net/en/Overview.aspx&quot; title=&quot;Shotty&quot;&gt;Shotty&lt;/a&gt;. One of the things I like about it is that it leaves the shadows of your screenshots intact which makes them look a lot nicer. It may not be essential to everybody but since I need to take screenshots from time to time I feel that it has it&amp;rsquo;s spot in this list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>December  5, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/05/apps-for-windows</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Setup</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sites on the web is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://usesthis.com/&quot; title=&quot;The Setup&quot;&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;. The tagline for it is &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do people use to get stuff done?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, which describes the purpose of it really well. It may be the nerd in me but I find it completely fascinating to see what kind of gear and software people in all kind of job fields use&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121202-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121202-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked it out and you&amp;rsquo;re as geeky as I am I suggest that you should. There&amp;rsquo;s also a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://usesthis.com/community/&quot; title=&quot;The Setup's Community&quot;&gt;spin-offs&lt;/a&gt; of the whole idea, which ranges from Linux users to teachers to people with disabilities. I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of doing something like that but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time nor the resources to do so just yet. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s a little fantastic website that I thoroughly enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121202-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler alert:&lt;/strong&gt; mostly Apple products, although both Linux and Windows users show up from time to time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121202-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>December  2, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/02/the-setup</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>