<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, musings and geekiness</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com/</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>stereokai.vim</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve really started to enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monokai.nl/blog/2006/07/15/textmate-color-theme/&quot; title=&quot;Monokai&quot;&gt;the Monokai theme&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a couple of different versions out there for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; and my favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jaromero/vim-monokai-refined&quot; title=&quot;Monokai-Refined on Github&quot;&gt;Monokai-Refined&lt;/a&gt;. However, Vim’s way of handling highlighting can sometimes be quite weird so I decided to add some minor tweaks so that it looks especially good when your writing HTML, CSS and Javascript and make it available in a repository. I don’t know if it’ll replace my beloved &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriskempson/tomorrow-theme&quot; title=&quot;Tomorrow Theme on Github&quot;&gt;Tomorrow Theme&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized&quot; title=&quot;Solarized&quot;&gt;Solarized&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s definitively a close third atleast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>May  9, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/05/09/stereokai-vim</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Responsive Inspector</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A pretty nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/responsive-inspector-beta/memcdolmmnmnleeiodllgpibdjlkbpim&quot; title=&quot;Responsive Inspector&quot;&gt;Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; for viewing the different defined media queries of a website. I sort of feel like a really nerd when I use it but the curiosity takes the best of me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>May  6, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/05/06/responsive-inspector</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A brand new blog (again)</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided yet again to throw together a new design for this site. At this point it feels like it’s almost getting a monthly thing, but hopefully I’ll stick with this one for a bit longer. I do really feel that I’m getting a bit better every time I do it though, which is something. This time around I took a much more &lt;a href=&quot;http://oocss.org/&quot; title=&quot;OOCSS&quot;&gt;OOCSS&lt;/a&gt; approach to the writing of the CSS and I mainly used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com/2013/01/mindbemding-getting-your-head-round-bem-syntax/&quot; title=&quot;MindBEMding – getting your head ’round BEM syntax&quot;&gt;BEM&lt;/a&gt; syntax. I don’t find it particularly pretty but it’s quite logical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I did was that instead of prefixing the classes of every major part of the site with &lt;code&gt;site-&lt;/code&gt; I went for a much simpler &lt;code&gt;l-&lt;/code&gt;, which stands for “layout”. I also used &lt;code&gt;br-&lt;/code&gt;, “breakpoint”, for the buttons in the main navigation. They get much wider when the site’s viewed on a small screen and instead of having to write a lot of code I simply added a class to them. Very convenient! If I had more “media query”-based classes I probably would’ve used other names for them, but as of right now it works well I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once again used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;’ excellent &lt;code&gt;darken&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lighten&lt;/code&gt; functions to generate the color palette. I can’t imagine how I’d do without them, to be honest. Like I mentioned earlier I feel that I’m getting better at designing in general but I’m not designer by far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally added syntax highlighting too. For some reason I completely missed that &lt;a href=&quot;http://softwaremaniacs.org/soft/highlight/en/&quot; title=&quot;Highlight.js&quot;&gt;Highlight.js&lt;/a&gt;, the engine that I now use, actually detects the language automatically without me having to add classes and span tags by hand. All the code is suddenly much more readable! I removed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; keybindings script for the site. It was getting on my nerves and the code looked truly awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s a wrap!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>May  2, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/05/02/a-brand-new-blog-again</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>SVGO</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A pretty awesome SVG optimizer, written with &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot; title=&quot;Node.js&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;. I tried it on a small logo file out of curiosity  and it went down from about 3 kb to 0.5 kb, which is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>April 25, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/04/25/svgo</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Scriptlr.js</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was getting sick of adding &lt;code&gt;script&lt;/code&gt; tags in my markup so I wrote a little script that could make it a bit more bearable. What it does is basically looping through an array of files, creating a new tag for each and every script and appends it to the body of the document. It’s obviously not meant to be used in production, but It’s quite handy when you want to play around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>April 22, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/04/22/scriptlr-js</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>
