<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random Ramblings, Overall Geekiness And Other Musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Setup</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sites on the web is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://usesthis.com/&quot; title=&quot;The Setup&quot;&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;. The tagline for it is &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do people use to get stuff done?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, which describes the purpose of it really well. It may be the nerd in me but I find it completely fascinating to see what kind of gear and software people in all kind of job fields use&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121202-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121202-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked it out and you&amp;rsquo;re as geeky as I am I suggest that you should. There&amp;rsquo;s also a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://usesthis.com/community/&quot; title=&quot;The Setup's Community&quot;&gt;spin-offs&lt;/a&gt; of the whole idea, which ranges from Linux users to teachers to people with disabilities. I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of doing something like that but haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time nor the resources to do so just yet. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s a little fantastic website that I thoroughly enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121202-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler alert:&lt;/strong&gt; mostly Apple products, although both Linux and Windows users show up from time to time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121202-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>December  2, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/12/02/the-setup</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Small Steps Into Ruby</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to learn a real programming language. The few times in the past that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried have all been fruitless though. My brain just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work when there&amp;rsquo;s too many complex structures going on at once. Even though I can understand the logic behind certain parts it just won&amp;rsquo;t stick, which is a shame. One of the reasons I think I like writing HTML and and especially CSS is that the syntax is very visual and easy to read. You write &lt;code&gt;background-color: red;&lt;/code&gt; and what do you know, the background suddenly is red. With those two you don&amp;rsquo;t have write a short novel just to get the command line to print a simple &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this site is built with Jekyll I decided to really start learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruby-lang.org/&quot; title=&quot;Ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. The syntax is so simple that it amazes me. Over the last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with it a lot and even released a few simple scripts on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. One of those was inspired by a post I saw yesterday on 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5963597/why-you-should-be-using-an-app-launcher-and-how-to-make-it-do-anythingyou-want&quot; title=&quot;Lifehacker&quot;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt;. The article mentions how you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://launchy.net/&quot; title=&quot;Launchy&quot;&gt;Launchy&lt;/a&gt; to append text to a text file, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the &lt;code&gt;bat&lt;/code&gt; script they recommended to properly work so I decided to just make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/append-text&quot; title=&quot;Append Text (for Launchy on GitHub&quot;&gt;Ruby version of it&lt;/a&gt;. The script looks like this without comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;require 'yaml'

config = YAML.load_file(&quot;config.yml&quot;)
txt_file = config[&quot;txt_file&quot;]

item = ARGV.join(&quot; &quot;)

File.open(txt_file, &quot;a&quot;) { |file| file.puts(item) }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now it consists of just five lines of code. I could&amp;rsquo;ve even made it even simpler by leaving out the use of YAML&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121128-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121128-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for the text file configuration&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121128-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121128-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I really like having something like that though since you don&amp;rsquo;t have to change the actual source code if you later decide to use another text file. Now I just need to launch Launchy, type &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TAB&lt;/code&gt; and whatever I want to append to the file and just hit &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; to add something to my spark file, which is even faster than launching the actually text file with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autohotkey.com/&quot; title=&quot;AutoHotKey&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt; like I mentioned in the previous blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humblelittlerubybook.com/book/&quot; title=&quot;Mr. Neighborly's Humble Little Ruby Book&quot;&gt;Mr. Neighborly&amp;rsquo;s Humble Little Ruby Book&lt;/a&gt; extremely good. It explains a lot of stuff without getting too technically complex and with a perfect mix of humor. Another book I also found helpful and easy to understand was &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby.bastardsbook.com/&quot; title=&quot;The Bastards Book of Ruby&quot;&gt;The Bastards Book of Ruby&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby.learncodethehardway.org/book/&quot; title=&quot;Learn Ruby The Hard Way&quot;&gt;Learn Ruby The Hard Way&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pine.fm/LearnToProgram/&quot; title=&quot;Learn To Program&quot;&gt;Learn To Program&lt;/a&gt; being mentioned quite a few times but so far I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to check them out. Another tip is that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the power of Google and a thriving community. &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/ruby&quot; title=&quot;Stack Overflow&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; is filled with a lot of answers for literally every single question you might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a long way to go, but so far it&amp;rsquo;s been a really fun ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121128-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yaml&quot; title=&quot;YAML Ain't Markup Language&quot;&gt;YAML Ain&amp;rsquo;t Markup Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121128-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121128-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file contains a single line, &lt;code&gt;txt_file:&lt;/code&gt;, where you put the path to the text file in question. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121128-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 28, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/28/small-steps-into-ruby</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Spark File</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I came across a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot; title=&quot;Medium&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-writers-room/8d6e7df7ae58&quot; title=&quot;The Spark File&quot;&gt;The Spark File&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenbjohnson&quot; title=&quot;Steven Johnson&quot;&gt;Steven Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. I really liked the idea of having a spark file of some sort but never took the time to try it out. I usually depend on &lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to jotting down ideas but more often than not I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with text files with just a headline in them, like &amp;ldquo;write about x and y&amp;rdquo;. While it definitively helps me remembering what I want to write about I feel that it&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary to have a ton of one line ideas clutter up my notes. That&amp;rsquo;s where the spark file fits perfectly. I finally understood that it&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;ll be a good addition to my writing workflow. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to only use ResophNotes for my blog posts or other types of writing when an idea has involved to something more solid, while the spark file is just a scratchpad for things I want to write about but haven&amp;rsquo;t really figured out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instant-sparks&quot;&gt;Instant Sparks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw together a simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autohotkey.com/&quot; title=&quot;AutoHotKey&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt; script so the spark file is just one hotkey away:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;!q::
{
Run, Notepad.exe &quot;~/spark-file.txt&quot;
Return
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that whenever an idea pops up I just need to press &lt;code&gt;Alt+Q&lt;/code&gt; and type down whatever&amp;rsquo;s in my head. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple but powerful solution that&amp;rsquo;ll serve me well I think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 26, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/26/the-spark-file</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Why (And How) I Wrote My Academic Book In Plain Text</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lengthy, comprehensive and informative article about why even academics should use plain text instead of Word whenever possible. I think it captures the idea of why you should use the format perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Via: &lt;a href=&quot;http://semicolons.net/post/36156007526/plain-text-is-where-ideas-can-grow-and-flourish&quot; title=&quot;Studies in Semicolons&quot;&gt;Studies in Semicolons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 23, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/23/why-and-how-i-wrote-my-academic-book-in-plain-text</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Better Structure</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog post can sometimes become quite tricky. There are those times when you&amp;rsquo;re banging on your keyboard and you&amp;rsquo;ve instantly come up with something actually worth posting, other times you only write three or four incoherent sentences at the most. In that kind of situation I usually just leave it until I can figure out the direction I want to go down, but unfortunately that can be hard too. Sometimes you really do need a place to jot down all of your ideas around a particular subject in a more structured way, like using an outliner. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen quite a bit of praise for one called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnioutliner/&quot; title=&quot;OmniOutliner&quot;&gt;OmniOutliner&lt;/a&gt; so I decided to look something similar. After som digging I came across an app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://uvoutliner.com/&quot; title=&quot;UV Outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/a&gt; and as I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself using it more and more I can really say that it&amp;rsquo;s a worthy alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uv-outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UV Outliner is like many of the apps I use free of charge. It&amp;rsquo;s also incredibly lightweight. The size of the installer is just around 1.5 MB and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get that much bigger once it&amp;rsquo;s installed on your system. The learning curve is virtually non-existent. You create nested levels by simply indenting your current line of text by pressing the &lt;code&gt;Tab&lt;/code&gt; key&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121122-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121122-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. All the of the nested levels are also collapsable and expandable by pressing either &lt;code&gt;Shift + Alt + -&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Shift + Alt + +&lt;/code&gt;. It also has support for multiple columns but I haven&amp;rsquo;t used that extensively at all. You can also add checkboxes to all of your lines of text, which makes it possible to use UV Outliner as a quite good task manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2012-11-22-uv-outliner.png&quot; alt=&quot;UV Outliner&quot; title=&quot;UV Outliner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change fonts, colors and add different backgrounds for even and odd rows of text. The font size for the different levels can also be changed. There&amp;rsquo;s unfortunately no way to save your customizations into a template so you have redo them every time in case you want to use them in all of your outline files. You have a choice to select a global font though which will get saved. UV Outliner can export your outlines into both rich text format, HTML and plain text but there&amp;rsquo;s no support for OPML&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121122-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121122-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m currently only using an outliner on my computer I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to export anything but I&amp;rsquo;m glad that the plain text alternative is atleast there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it exports to rich text format the app also support basic formatting like bold and italicized text for example, which often comes in handy. I personally use bold text as a way to tell myself that there&amp;rsquo;s another level of nested text to that specific line just because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to fiddle too much with the look of the outline. Another smart little function in the app is the ability to add so called inline notes. These notes gets placed under your text and can be useful when you want to note to something but don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to have it in your actual outline. They won&amp;rsquo;t get exported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap things up: I think that overall it&amp;rsquo;s a nice app which comes in handy for brainstorming and organsing the work that goes in to writing blog posts among other things. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I&amp;rsquo;m going to use it all the time but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have something like it when you&amp;rsquo;re stuck and you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121122-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shift + Tab&lt;/code&gt; brings it back up a level.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121122-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121122-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opml&quot; title=&quot;OPML&quot;&gt;Outline Processor Markup Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121122-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 22, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/22/a-better-structure</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>