<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random Ramblings, Overall Geekiness And Other Musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Spark File</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I came across a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot; title=&quot;Medium&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-writers-room/8d6e7df7ae58&quot; title=&quot;The Spark File&quot;&gt;The Spark File&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenbjohnson&quot; title=&quot;Steven Johnson&quot;&gt;Steven Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. I really liked the idea of having a spark file of some sort but never took the time to try it out. I usually depend on &lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to jotting down ideas but more often than not I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with text files with just a headline in them, like &amp;ldquo;write about x and y&amp;rdquo;. While it definitively helps me remembering what I want to write about I feel that it&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary to have a ton of one line ideas clutter up my notes. That&amp;rsquo;s where the spark file fits perfectly. I finally understood that it&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;ll be a good addition to my writing workflow. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to only use ResophNotes for my blog posts or other types of writing when an idea has involved to something more solid, while the spark file is just a scratchpad for things I want to write about but haven&amp;rsquo;t really figured out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instant-sparks&quot;&gt;Instant Sparks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw together a simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autohotkey.com/&quot; title=&quot;AutoHotKey&quot;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt; script so the spark file is just one hotkey away:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;!q::
{
Run, Notepad.exe &quot;~/spark-file.txt&quot;
Return
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that whenever an idea pops up I just need to press &lt;code&gt;Alt+Q&lt;/code&gt; and type down whatever&amp;rsquo;s in my head. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple but powerful solution that&amp;rsquo;ll serve me well I think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 26, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/26/the-spark-file</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Why (And How) I Wrote My Academic Book In Plain Text</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lengthy, comprehensive and informative article about why even academics should use plain text instead of Word whenever possible. I think it captures the idea of why you should use the format perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Via: &lt;a href=&quot;http://semicolons.net/post/36156007526/plain-text-is-where-ideas-can-grow-and-flourish&quot; title=&quot;Studies in Semicolons&quot;&gt;Studies in Semicolons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 23, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/23/why-and-how-i-wrote-my-academic-book-in-plain-text</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Better Structure</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog post can sometimes become quite tricky. There are those times when you&amp;rsquo;re banging on your keyboard and you&amp;rsquo;ve instantly come up with something actually worth posting, other times you only write three or four incoherent sentences at the most. In that kind of situation I usually just leave it until I can figure out the direction I want to go down, but unfortunately that can be hard too. Sometimes you really do need a place to jot down all of your ideas around a particular subject in a more structured way, like using an outliner. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen quite a bit of praise for one called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnioutliner/&quot; title=&quot;OmniOutliner&quot;&gt;OmniOutliner&lt;/a&gt; so I decided to look something similar. After som digging I came across an app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://uvoutliner.com/&quot; title=&quot;UV Outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/a&gt; and as I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself using it more and more I can really say that it&amp;rsquo;s a worthy alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uv-outliner&quot;&gt;UV Outliner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UV Outliner is like many of the apps I use free of charge. It&amp;rsquo;s also incredibly lightweight. The size of the installer is just around 1.5 MB and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get that much bigger once it&amp;rsquo;s installed on your system. The learning curve is virtually non-existent. You create nested levels by simply indenting your current line of text by pressing the &lt;code&gt;Tab&lt;/code&gt; key&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121122-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121122-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. All the of the nested levels are also collapsable and expandable by pressing either &lt;code&gt;Shift + Alt + -&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Shift + Alt + +&lt;/code&gt;. It also has support for multiple columns but I haven&amp;rsquo;t used that extensively at all. You can also add checkboxes to all of your lines of text, which makes it possible to use UV Outliner as a quite good task manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2012-11-22-uv-outliner.png&quot; alt=&quot;UV Outliner&quot; title=&quot;UV Outliner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change fonts, colors and add different backgrounds for even and odd rows of text. The font size for the different levels can also be changed. There&amp;rsquo;s unfortunately no way to save your customizations into a template so you have redo them every time in case you want to use them in all of your outline files. You have a choice to select a global font though which will get saved. UV Outliner can export your outlines into both rich text format, HTML and plain text but there&amp;rsquo;s no support for OPML&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121122-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121122-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m currently only using an outliner on my computer I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to export anything but I&amp;rsquo;m glad that the plain text alternative is atleast there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it exports to rich text format the app also support basic formatting like bold and italicized text for example, which often comes in handy. I personally use bold text as a way to tell myself that there&amp;rsquo;s another level of nested text to that specific line just because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to fiddle too much with the look of the outline. Another smart little function in the app is the ability to add so called inline notes. These notes gets placed under your text and can be useful when you want to note to something but don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to have it in your actual outline. They won&amp;rsquo;t get exported either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap things up: I think that overall it&amp;rsquo;s a nice app which comes in handy for brainstorming and organsing the work that goes in to writing blog posts among other things. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I&amp;rsquo;m going to use it all the time but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have something like it when you&amp;rsquo;re stuck and you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121122-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shift + Tab&lt;/code&gt; brings it back up a level.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121122-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121122-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opml&quot; title=&quot;OPML&quot;&gt;Outline Processor Markup Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121122-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 22, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/22/a-better-structure</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Perfect Typeface</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of both serif and sans-serifs I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been comfortable with using them for any serious writing unless I really, eally had to. I&amp;rsquo;m a monospace lover through and through. Somehow those types of fonts feel more natural to write with for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://dejavu-fonts.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot; title=&quot;DejaVu Fonts&quot;&gt;DejaVu Sans Mono&lt;/a&gt; for a long time but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that it&amp;rsquo;s not really the best typeface for me and my eyes. It&amp;rsquo;s too bold and looks quite chunky with some rough edges&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121119-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121119-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It works alright for coding, but I feel like I get a bit lost when I try to read the actual words that I&amp;rsquo;d just written. I knew that it had to be some better alternatives out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://levien.com/type/myfonts/inconsolata.html&quot; title=&quot;Inconsolata&quot;&gt;Inconsolata&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent typeface. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look too good when you&amp;rsquo;re using it in smaller sizes&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20121119-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20121119-2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I find it absolutely delightful to use with the size set at about 21px and line-height at 125% when I&amp;rsquo;m typing away in &lt;a href=&quot;http://gottcode.org/focuswriter/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter&quot;&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/a&gt;. It may look a bit too thin for some, but for it&amp;rsquo;s just what I need. I usually try sit at a comfortable distance from my screen so the thinness is not really that bad at all. I also tend to use pretty neutral colors in the grayscale range which typically works good with any kind of typeface. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2012-11-19-inconsolata.png&quot; alt=&quot;Inconsolata In FocusWriter&quot; title=&quot;Inconsolata In FocusWriter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hunt for something better is finally over and hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll make me be more productive when it comes to writing. I&amp;rsquo;d like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121119-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The font rendering on Windows is quite horrendous from time to time.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121119-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20121119-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Another common Windows font rendering problem.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20121119-2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 19, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/19/the-perfect-typeface</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>in:play</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Where has this app been all my life? I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a massive fan of using the iPhone as a music player, but this might change that. It&amp;rsquo;s geniusly simple and equally gorgeous. It&amp;rsquo;s also 50% off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Via: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5960804/inplay-is-a-minimalist-gestureBased-music-player-for-the-iphone&quot; title=&quot;Lifehacker&quot;&gt;Lifehacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>November 16, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/11/16/in-play</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>