<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Gummesson 2.0</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make the jump and thus this site now has a spanking new design. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Oswald&quot; title=&quot;Oswald&quot;&gt;Oswald&lt;/a&gt; is used for the headings and the navigation and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Asap&quot; title=&quot;Asap&quot;&gt;Asap&lt;/a&gt; is used for the body copy. I quite like them together since the former has a kind of slab-serif quality to it, even though it's actually a sans-serif. The bold and italic versions of Asap aren't perfect, but they look much better than than they did before. I haven't had the chance you check out how they look in &lt;em&gt;Firefox&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Opera&lt;/em&gt;, but I hope they look good in them too. I've also increased the font size from 112.5% &lt;em&gt;(which usually equals to 18px)&lt;/em&gt; to 125% &lt;em&gt;(20px)&lt;/em&gt; just because I'm a big fan of having a bigger size for readability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 10, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/10/gummesson-two-point-zero</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Redesigning</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though this site isn't even a month old I'm having serious thoughts about redesigning it. In fact, I already have a design that's about 99% finished. I'm having a hard time deciding if I really should switch or not though. One minute I'm liking the current design (atleast the basic structure of it) and the next I dislike it. One thing I really don't like with it is that the default typeface used for the body copy (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Vollkorn&quot;&gt;Vollkorn&lt;/a&gt;) looks really nice as long as you don't use the bold and italic font styles on your text. The bold looks really heavy compared to the normal weight and that bugs me quite much. The italic version looks okay, but I'm not totally happy with it. The typography is a big part of this site's design (if not the only part) since I'm not a really graphical designer (I wouldn't even call myself a designer, to be honest).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight I probably should've spent more time on choosing the right typefaces earlier, but I was eager to launch this site so I didn't. So, I guess the conclusion of this post is that I'll likely change the typefaces, but stick to the one column layout. I'm thinking about cleaning up the code a bit too, but we'll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September  7, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/07/redesigning</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Hard (Drive) Failure</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago my new hard drive that I bought a mere three weeks ago decided that it was time to make my life not so fun by giving up. For some reason it failed, and it failed hard. Luckily, I had all of my important files (like this whole site) stored on an external drive and I have a SSD where I can keep my OS and all of my programs and such, but some of my other files are forever lost. It sucks, but I'll survive. My brother (who really helped med out) fought like a champ trying to get it to work, but it was a lost cause. In the process of trying to save my new hard drive I also had to wipe my SSD too. It took quite a while to install everything again, but now it's all up and running. The &quot;failed to sync branch&quot; problem I had earlier with GitHub is also gone, which I guess you could say is good, even though I would've rather had that problem than going trough this whole ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't really know if I'm more sad or more angry though. Sure, it's really important that you take backups of everything that you want to keep and store, but I don't think I really can blame myself entirely in this case. I mean, you don't really except a hard drive that you've barely used to break down and just fail on you so suddenly. On the other hand I do want to kick myself in the head, atleast just a little bit. Oh well. Sometimes we think that computers are these indestructible things that can do no wrong, but I guess that's not really the case. Now I'm keeping my fingers crossed that I can get it replaced without any hassles, but that shouldn't really be a problem. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September  5, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/05/a-hard-drive-failure</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>My Jekyll Workflow</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I've had this blog for a while I thought it would be a good idea to write about how my so called workflow looks to wrap this whole Jekyll series up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Writing in MarkdownPad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first fire up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markdownpad.com/&quot;&gt;MarkdownPad&lt;/a&gt; and start writing a new blog post. It's a really nifty little tool for us Mac-depraved Windows users. I use DejaVu Sans Mono (which is my choice for coding purposes too) as my default font with &lt;code&gt;#FF434343&lt;/code&gt; as the font color and &lt;code&gt;#FFF2F2F2&lt;/code&gt; as the background color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Running Jekyll locally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I'm done with my writing, I fire up the command line and run Jekyll to generate my site. I also skim through my blog post to make sure that I haven't accidentally made a typo or something to that effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Pushing to GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, I open up &lt;a href=&quot;http://windows.github.com/&quot; title=&quot;GitHub for Windows&quot;&gt;GitHub for Windows&lt;/a&gt; and push my site to GitHub. Even though it's not the most convenient thing to do it's still pretty easy and it makes the transfer so much faster with no hassles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Note:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub Pages (where I host my site) can actually run Jekyll and generate your site automatically but you can't use your own plugins, so that's why I'm deploying my static pages rather than just the source itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's it! You could argue that it sounds a lot like overkill, but it works for me. Sure, I can't upgrade something without sitting infront of my computer, but I know that I'd never update from a phone or email anyways. It really makes me think twice before I publish something too, which I like.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September  2, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/02/my-jekyll-workflow</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>More Additions</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Being bored sometimes has it's own perks. I continued experimenting with the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/begrider/&quot;&gt;Begider&lt;/a&gt; project and ended up adding a couple of more things to it, mainly a new set of column-like classes called &lt;code&gt;.unit-&lt;/code&gt;. A unit differ itself from a regular column by not having a gutter, and thus having more of a &quot;proportional&quot; percentage width. So, instead of just having these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.row .column-twelve {
  width: 99.99%;
  margin-right: 0;
}

.row .column-eleven {
  width: 91.42%;
}

.row .column-ten {
  width: 82.85%;
}

/* Nine columns */
.row .column-nine {
  width: 74.28%;
}

.row .column-eight {
  width: 65.71%;
}

.row .column-seven {
  width: 57.14%;
}

.row .column-six {
  width: 48.57%;
}

.row .column-five {
  width: 40%;
}

.row .column-four {
  width: 31.43%;
}

.row .column-three {
  width: 22.86%;
}

.row .column-two {
  width: 14.29%;
}

.row .column-one {
  width: 5.72%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.row .unit-full {
  width: 100%;
}

.row .unit-four-fifths {
  width: 80%;
}

.row .unit-three-quarters {
  width: 75%;
}

.row .unit-two-thirds {
  width: 66.66%;
}

.row .unit-three-fifths {
  width: 60%;
}

.row .unit-half {
  width: 50%;
}

.row .unit-two-fifths {
  width: 40%;
}

.row .unit-one-third {
  width: 33.33%;
}

.row .unit-one-quarter {
  width: 25%;
}

.row .unit-one-fifth {
  width: 20%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's useful if you don't want to have any gutters and/or want to use paddings instead instead of margins. I don't know if anyone's ever going to use besides myself, but I quite like to work on it either way. Like I said, it keeps my boredom at bay. I don't really know if it actually needs anything more, but I'll be sure to try stuff out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>August 31, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/08/31/more-additions</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>