<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random Ramblings, Overall Geekiness And Other Musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com/</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Vimium: The Hacker's Browser</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably the last person on earth to discover this neat little extension but it&amp;rsquo;s nonetheless a great thing for both navigating in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/chrome&quot; title=&quot;Chrome&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and learning the basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot; title=&quot;Vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 18, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/18/vimium</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>I Created Yet Another (Pointless) App</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My experiments with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sinatra&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; framework continues and yesterday I pushed yet another app to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heroku.com/&quot; title=&quot;Heroku&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;http://slugize.ellengummesson.com/&quot; title=&quot;Slugize&quot;&gt;Slugize&lt;/a&gt;. It only has one small purpose: creating a slug out of a blog title, which can be pretty handy when you use a static site generator like &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t decide on a title until a few seconds before I &amp;ldquo;hit publish&amp;rdquo; which means that fixing the slug is usually the last thing I do. I find it extremely annoying that I have to manually type out &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; between every word in the title and change every letter to be in downcase&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130115-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130115-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I guess you can call it lazyiness too. Now I only need to copy and paste the title into &lt;em&gt;Slugize&lt;/em&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;ll do it automatically for me and I also added an option to append the current day&amp;rsquo;s date to it. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how being lazy sometimes makes you more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130115-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I do actually use the &lt;code&gt;rake post&lt;/code&gt; function that I created for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/jekyll-rake-boilerplate&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll Rake Boilerplate&quot;&gt;Jekyll Rake Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt; project, but I only use it when I&amp;rsquo;m 100% sure on a post&amp;rsquo;s title and content.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130115-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 15, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/15/i-created-yet-another-pointless-app</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Launch Week</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finally pushed something to the master branch of a thing I started working on last week, &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; title=&quot;Smallwork&quot;&gt;Smallwork&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small yet full featured &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot; title=&quot;SCSS&quot;&gt;SCSS&lt;/a&gt; framework, or starting point as I&amp;rsquo;d like to call it. The first time I tried SCSS was way back in August or September but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it until I started learning Ruby. The code length measures in at a total of 1156 numbers of lines&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20130112-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:20130112-1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which kind of makes it my most ambitious work to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also played around with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sinatra&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; again and came up with a simple journal app which uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://datamapper.org/&quot; title=&quot;Datamapper&quot;&gt;Datamapper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sqlite.org/&quot; title=&quot;SQLite 3&quot;&gt;SQLite3&lt;/a&gt; for storing everything in a database. Like I mentioned earlier I&amp;rsquo;m quite fond of Sinatra, especially since it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to understand what do to and what&amp;rsquo;s going on. The code is so self-explanatory that I sometimes have to pinch myself to see that I&amp;rsquo;m not in fact dreaming. I&amp;rsquo;m no expert but I like where I&amp;rsquo;m going with it and I&amp;rsquo;ve barely scratched the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also thinking about extending &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramit.ellengummesson.com/&quot; title=&quot;Kramit!&quot;&gt;Kramit!&lt;/a&gt; a bit, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes&amp;hellip; I guess I should try to slow myself down a bit since I&amp;rsquo;ve launched three new projects this week alone. I&amp;rsquo;m having fun though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:20130112-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s including blank lines and comments. It&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty big number though. The compiled CSS code is 682 lines long and that&amp;rsquo;s without any additional content besides the basic structure itself.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:20130112-1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 12, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/12/launch-week</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Lo And Behold, I've Launched An Web App!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The day before yesterday I launched my first &amp;ldquo;web app&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramit.ellengummesson.com/&quot; title=&quot;Kramit!&quot;&gt;Kramit!&lt;/a&gt;. Like about half a million people on the internet with some kind of web development interest I created yet another &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot; title=&quot;Markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; preview app and with the wonderful micro web framework &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Sinatra&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing unique but I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud nonetheless. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually seen that many that uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramdown.rubyforge.org/&quot; title=&quot;Kramdown&quot;&gt;Kramdown&lt;/a&gt; as it&amp;rsquo;s default parser, so I guess that that aspect is somewhat pretty unique&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-minimum-than-an-mvp&quot;&gt;More Minimum Than An MVP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kramit!&lt;/em&gt; is at it&amp;rsquo;s core the definition of an MVP&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The whole thing consists of just 33 lines of Sinatra code, 61 lines of HTML for the views (ie. the layout) and 243 lines of CSS for both the app itself and the preview. A total of 337 lines. That&amp;rsquo;s nothing! I&amp;rsquo;m quite amazed that Sinatra makes me able to do so much with barely any code at all. It literally took me just a few hours to go from idea to launch and the hard part wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually writing the code but rather designing it.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;So, What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all I think I&amp;rsquo;m continue to play around with Sinatra and the Ruby language itself a bit more and then maybe look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org/&quot; title=&quot;Ruby on Rails&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s much more advanced and kind of plays on a whole other field than Sinatra, but it would be fun to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I like it because it has &lt;a href=&quot;http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/&quot; title=&quot;MultiMarkdown&quot;&gt;MultiMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; features like footnotes for examples (this footnote became very meta by the way).&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product&quot; title=&quot;Minimum viable product&quot;&gt;Minimum viable product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I would called myself challenged in that department. My basic design process is &amp;ldquo;make something up, strip away all the things that I though was going to look good but didn&amp;rsquo;t, look it at it again and then remove some more&amp;rdquo;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; rel=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <published>January 10, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/10/lo-and-behold-ive-launched-an-web-app</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Smalify: Minification On The Fly</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this little gem of an app earlier today and I got to say that it was just what I was looking for and needed. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to minify my code for some time but I haven&amp;rsquo;t found something simple that could do that. There are some web based apps and services out there that can do it, but I like having a native solution so that it can update itself whenever there&amp;rsquo;s a new change and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>January  7, 2013</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2013/01/07/smalify-minification-on-the-fly</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>