<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>My New Twitter Client</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After a hectic search for a replacement for &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.echofon.com/2012/10/changes-coming-for-echofon-desktop-users.html&quot; title=&quot;Echofon&quot;&gt;Echofon&lt;/a&gt; I think I've finally stumbled upon something that'll work for me, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotot.org/&quot; title=&quot;Hotot&quot;&gt;Hotot&lt;/a&gt;. Like many apps I use it's both open source and cross platform though it's mainly developed for the Linux environment. Although the website states that the Windows version is &quot;very unstable&quot; I haven't had any problems with it yet. It's not as pretty and clean as Echofon but the fact that it's still decently minimal and it has a one column layout makes it worth using in my opinion. I did try out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sobees.com/social-media-clients/sobees-desktop-application&quot; title=&quot;Sobees&quot;&gt;Sobees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nymphicusapp.com/windows/&quot; title=&quot;Nymphicus&quot;&gt;Nymphicus&lt;/a&gt;. For some reason Sobees wouldn't let me stay logged in and Nymphicus' interface didn't strike a chord with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-10-22-hotot.png' title='Hotot' alt='Hotot'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The login screen leaves a lot to be desired but I actually really like the buttons that's at the top of the default interface. It's quite reminiscent of Tapbots' &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter/id557168941?mt=12&quot; title=&quot;Tweetbot for Mac&quot;&gt;Tweetbot for Mac&lt;/a&gt;. I've noticed that it sometimes takes a couple of minutes for it to notify me about mentions and messages, but I think I'm just spoiled with other apps in that regard. I do hope that the development of it continues but I guess my backup plan is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://tweetdeck.com/&quot; title=&quot;Tweetdeck&quot;&gt;Tweetdeck&lt;/a&gt; since it's the official client for Twitter. I'm not it's biggest fan though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 22, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/22/my-new-twitter-client</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>How The Non-Existent Sony Nexus X Fooled The Tech World</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I faked the Sony Nexus X.&lt;/strong&gt; Truly sorry. But I did come away from the experience with a few observations. I will share these musings, along with how and why I created these fakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say that this is pretty damn impressive. Well played whoever you are, well played.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 20, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/20/how-the-non-existent-sony-nexus-x-fooled-the-tech-world</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Changes Coming For Echofon Desktop Users</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning this Fall, we will begin phasing out our Echofon desktop products (Mac, Windows, Firefox) in order to focus more on our mobile line of Echofon apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such a shame. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.echofon.com/&quot; title=&quot;Echofon&quot;&gt;Echofon&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best one column Twitter client for Windows users (if not the only one). I guess I need to find something else then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 18, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/18/changes-coming-for-echofon-desktop-users</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Find And Launch It</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate having a clouded desktop (it never looks good in my opinion) but I like to be able to open apps and documents really fast. As soon as an idea pops into my head I want to have the opportunity to write it down (or whatever I need to do) and run with it, so to speak. I've tried a minimal approach by just using the built-in search function in Windows 7 which is located in the start menu. It works okay for finding apps and such but the indexing of documents is horrendous to say the least. You can't really add and choose what you want to include either. While looking for a worthy alternative to it I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.launchy.net/&quot; title=&quot;Launchy&quot;&gt;Launchy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-10-16-launchy.png' title='Launchy' alt='Launchy'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launchy is an open source, cross platform (which means that it's right up my alley) utility application similiar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.apple.com/kb/ht2531&quot; title=&quot;Mac 101: Spotlight&quot;&gt;Spotlight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alfredapp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Alfred&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.obdev.at/products/launchbar/index.html&quot; title=&quot;LaunchBar&quot;&gt;LaunchBar&lt;/a&gt; for OS X. I've now used it for about a week or so and I can already tell that's it's going to be added to my essential apps list. It's fast, you can include and exclude anything you want, search the web, do simple math calculations and also change it's appearance (I use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://artblanc.deviantart.com/art/Loupe-for-Launchy-264482213&quot; title=&quot;Loupe for Launchy&quot;&gt;Loupe&lt;/a&gt; skin). It'll also learn what you mean when you search for something, which meaning that Launchy will list the thing that you use the most when you type in something that corresponds with the filename. An example for that is that when I search for the folder where I have my website, which is suprisingly called &quot;Jekyll&quot;, I only have to hit a simple &quot;j&quot; on my keyboard for it to pick up that I mean that particular folder. It's awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There's a lot of skins available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://browse.deviantart.com/customization/skins/applaunchers/launchy/&quot; title=&quot;Launchy Skins on DeviantART&quot;&gt;DeviantART&lt;/a&gt;, go check them out if you're looking for some nice alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 16, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/16/find-and-launch-it</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>An Intimate Portrait Of Innovation, Risk, And Failure Through Hipstamatic's Lens</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A behind the scenes look at the company &lt;a href=&quot;http://hipstamatic.com/&quot; title=&quot;Hipstamatic&quot;&gt;Hipstamatic&lt;/a&gt; and their past and present problems and the hardship that have risen with the success of Instagram and other companies alike. It's lengthy, but it's also a quite fascinating piece.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 14, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/14/an-intimate-portrait-of-innovation-risk-and-failure-through-hipstamatics-lens</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>