<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>Squarespace Note</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;​​A free minimalist iOS app that anyone can use to capture all their thoughts, ideas, and inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.squarespace.com/&quot; title=&quot;Squarespace&quot;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; just released a simple note taking app. I love the interface but I wish I could choose which folder in Dropbox that I want to sync my notes to, since I already have one for all the ones I've previously written. The app is completely free though so I shouldn't really complain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 26, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/26/squarespace-note</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The New iMac</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The thinness really amazes me. How is it even possible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 24, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/24/the-new-imac</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>My New Twitter Client</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After a hectic search for a replacement for &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.echofon.com/2012/10/changes-coming-for-echofon-desktop-users.html&quot; title=&quot;Echofon&quot;&gt;Echofon&lt;/a&gt; I think I've finally stumbled upon something that'll work for me, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotot.org/&quot; title=&quot;Hotot&quot;&gt;Hotot&lt;/a&gt;. Like many apps I use it's both open source and cross platform though it's mainly developed for the Linux environment. Although the website states that the Windows version is &quot;very unstable&quot; I haven't had any problems with it yet. It's not as pretty and clean as Echofon but the fact that it's still decently minimal and it has a one column layout makes it worth using in my opinion. I did try out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sobees.com/social-media-clients/sobees-desktop-application&quot; title=&quot;Sobees&quot;&gt;Sobees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nymphicusapp.com/windows/&quot; title=&quot;Nymphicus&quot;&gt;Nymphicus&lt;/a&gt;. For some reason Sobees wouldn't let me stay logged in and Nymphicus' interface didn't strike a chord with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-10-22-hotot.png' title='Hotot' alt='Hotot'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The login screen leaves a lot to be desired but I actually really like the buttons that's at the top of the default interface. It's quite reminiscent of Tapbots' &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter/id557168941?mt=12&quot; title=&quot;Tweetbot for Mac&quot;&gt;Tweetbot for Mac&lt;/a&gt;. I've noticed that it sometimes takes a couple of minutes for it to notify me about mentions and messages, but I think I'm just spoiled with other apps in that regard. I do hope that the development of it continues but I guess my backup plan is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://tweetdeck.com/&quot; title=&quot;Tweetdeck&quot;&gt;Tweetdeck&lt;/a&gt; since it's the official client for Twitter. I'm not it's biggest fan though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 22, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/22/my-new-twitter-client</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>How The Non-Existent Sony Nexus X Fooled The Tech World</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I faked the Sony Nexus X.&lt;/strong&gt; Truly sorry. But I did come away from the experience with a few observations. I will share these musings, along with how and why I created these fakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say that this is pretty damn impressive. Well played whoever you are, well played.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 20, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/20/how-the-non-existent-sony-nexus-x-fooled-the-tech-world</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Changes Coming For Echofon Desktop Users</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning this Fall, we will begin phasing out our Echofon desktop products (Mac, Windows, Firefox) in order to focus more on our mobile line of Echofon apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such a shame. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.echofon.com/&quot; title=&quot;Echofon&quot;&gt;Echofon&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best one column Twitter client for Windows users (if not the only one). I guess I need to find something else then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>October 18, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/10/18/changes-coming-for-echofon-desktop-users</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>