<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Short Note About The New iOS</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The battery life on my &lt;em&gt;iPhone 4S&lt;/em&gt; has improved when I'm not using 3G or WiFi...but it's gotten worse when I'm actually using something that requires an internet connection to work. Granted I only upgraded to &lt;em&gt;iOS 6&lt;/em&gt; about two days ago, so maybe it'll get better with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One step forward and one step back, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 21, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/21/a-short-note-about-the-new-ios</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>The Joys Of Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After about a month of what I would say is fairly regularly blogging on this website I've come to the conclusion that I really love to write, even though I'm not sure that anybody is actually reading it. A couple of years ago I toyed with the idea to actually study to become a journalist, but that didn't plan out. In hindsight, it was probably for the best. I did get a small freelance job as a music writer and reviewer that lasted about a year, which I enjoyed even though I think I got a bit repetitive at the end of the run. My newfound love of writing is probably what keeps me going. I haven't set up an &lt;em&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/em&gt; account nor a &lt;em&gt;FeedBurner&lt;/em&gt; either, just because I realize that statistics doesn't really matter much to me. Sure, I would be really happy to know that someone appreciate my writing and what I have to say, but I'm mostly doing it for the sake of myself. It doesn't hurt that I'm probably getting better and better at it either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 20, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/20/the-joys-of-writing</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>My Adventure With Peppermint OS</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I've always been a bit of a geek, so naturally I decided to try out a lightweight &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt; distro on my old computer &lt;em&gt;(mostly just for kicks)&lt;/em&gt;. I looked around on the internet and came across a couple of distros that looked good, and in the end I decided to try out &lt;a href=&quot;http://peppermintos.com/&quot; title=&quot;Peppermint OS&quot;&gt;Peppermint OS&lt;/a&gt;. The ISO file was small enough for me to burn it onto a CD rather than a DVD, plus I was confident &lt;em&gt;(well, as confident as you can be without having actually tried it)&lt;/em&gt; that my old computer could atleast handle it pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Peppermint OS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's an short introduction borrowed from the official website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peppermint was designed for enhanced mobility, efficiency and ease of use. While other operating systems are taking 10 minutes to load, you are already connected, communicating and getting things done. And, unlike other operating systems, Peppermint is ready to use out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though my old computer is borderline ancient, it took about 10-15 minutes at the most to install the whole thing &lt;em&gt;(I did run in to some problems at first, but it think that was the computer's fault rather than the actually OS itself)&lt;/em&gt;. The initial setup went smooth too, though it took a couple of minutes before my internet connection worked. So far I haven't been tweaking that much, but I'm defintively looking forward to doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-18-peppermint-os.png' title='Peppermint OS Three' alt='Peppermint OS Three'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that I've install a &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt; distro &lt;em&gt;(I've poked around in Ubuntu a few times)&lt;/em&gt; and I must say that so far I'm impressed. The next step for me is to try to customize it a bit, especially the look of the shell. I'm quite excited to dive in to the &lt;em&gt;(hopefully)&lt;/em&gt; wonderful world of &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt;. I might even get stuck in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 18, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/18/my-adventure-with-peppermint-os</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Cleaning Up</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last couple of days I've started to clean up among my RSS subscriptions. I'll admit that when I first started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/reader&quot; title=&quot;Google Reader&quot;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; a couple of years ago I subscribed and subscribed, and then subscribed some more. I became an feed addict. I started to add every site that I came across that I enjoyed, which adds up to a lot over a longer period of time. As you can imagine, it became more and more stressful to keep up with every single feed &lt;em&gt;(admittedly I didn't do a good job of doing that, but I atleast tried)&lt;/em&gt;. So I decided that it was time to do a serious clean up. I'm finally done after plowing through countless of feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think that it's more enjoyable to read all the posts as most of them were intended, ie. on an actual blog/website. Even though &lt;em&gt;Google Reader&lt;/em&gt; is a handy tool it's not very nice too look at, atleast not when you read a very long piece. I know that you can use extensions to make it more enjoyable, but I don't really like to have to many of those either. I do use &lt;a href=&quot;http://wwww.getpocket.com/&quot; title=&quot;Pocket&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; when I want to save something that I want to read later, especially when I know that I'm going to use my &lt;em&gt;iPhone&lt;/em&gt; for some late night reading. Even though my life won't change drastically just because I hit the unsubscribe button on some feeds it feels good to have less distractions in my life. Now I actually look forward to read something, which I haven't done in a long time. That's quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 17, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/17/cleaning-up</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Themes For FocusWriter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;By being bored and wanting to have something to do I made a couple of themes for &lt;em&gt;FocusWriter&lt;/em&gt; based on other editors like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iawriter.com/&quot; title=&quot;iA Writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bywordapp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Byword&quot;&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt; and color schemes like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized&quot; title=&quot;Solarized&quot;&gt;Solarized&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out some screenshots of them by either clicking on this post's title &lt;em&gt;(I finally get the chance to use an external link!)&lt;/em&gt; or right &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/focuswriter-themes/&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter Themes&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you'd rather want that. They're also available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gummesson/focuswriter-themes&quot; title=&quot;FocusWriter Themes on GitHub&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 15, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/15/themes-for-focuswriter</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>