<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Ellen Gummesson</title>
        <description>Random ramblings, overall geekiness and other musings</description>
          <link>http://ellengummesson.com</link>
            
              <item>
                <title>ResophNotes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most frequent mention apps I've seen around the web during the last couple of months is &lt;a href=&quot;http://notational.net/&quot; title=&quot;Notational Velocity&quot;&gt;Notational Velocity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(or rather a popular fork of it called &lt;a href=&quot;http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/&quot; title=&quot;nvALT&quot;&gt;nvALT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;. In short it's a note taking app where you can both create plain text notes and store, tag and search among them. You can also synch them synch with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dropbox.com/&quot; title=&quot;Dropbox&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(by creating a folder and storing your notes on your account)&lt;/em&gt; and a couple of other services, which enables you to access your files from pretty much anywhere as long as you have some kind of internet connection. Sadly it's only available for &lt;em&gt;Mac&lt;/em&gt; computers so I went out on my way to see if I could find an alternative. I did and it's name is &lt;a href=&quot;http://resoph.com/ResophNotes/Welcome.html&quot; title=&quot;ResophNotes&quot;&gt;ResophNotes&lt;/a&gt;, which was originally built as a Windows based app for &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplenoteapp.com/&quot; title=&quot;Simplenote&quot;&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt; but you can also use it with &lt;em&gt;Dropbox&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2012-09-13-resophnotes.png' title='ResophNotes' alt='ResophNotes'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's maybe not be pretty as it's &lt;em&gt;Apple&lt;/em&gt; counterparts, but the foundation is the same. It's nice to have all of your notes in the same place, and I really like that you're able to tag them. It means that I can place all of my blog post ideas in a tag called &quot;blog&quot; and so on. It also has a lot of options, meaning you can customize it to your liking. For example, I'm planning to hide all of the icons once I've learned all of the shortcuts properly since I like a more clean cut look. I've been only using it for a couple of days, but so far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 13, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/13/resophnotes</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>External Links In The Post Title</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I finally managed to add the ability to have external links in my post titles on this site. I tried and I tried, but for some reason I couldn't get it to work properly. I waited a couple of days and tried again and then boom, it worked. I don't know what I did wrong the first time, but I'm glad that it now works. Thanks to the YAML Front Matter and Liquid tags it's actually not that hard to add to your site. I don't really know if I'll use it that much, but I quite like to have that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to add the external links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following markup is a simplified version of what I use. You should modify it to your liking and preferably add alt and title tags to your links. First, add this in the front matter portion of your post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;external-link: http://www.example.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to add an external link to your title, just replace the link itself with &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; or remove the whole thing. The markup of your post title on your front page should look like something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of having the above markup, replace it with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% if post.external-link %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.external-link }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% else %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ post.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% endif %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added this in the markup for my post layout:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% if page.external-link %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ page.external-link }}&quot;&amp;gt;{{ page.title }}&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% else %}
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;{{ page.title }}&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
{% endif %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you're done! I would encourage you to also add an actual permalink to your own post if you're using external links, like this for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ post.url }}&quot;&amp;gt;Permalink&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A side note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually had to add another plugin so I could show the Liquid tags since Jekyll parses them automatically. You can find it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/1020852&quot; title=&quot;Raw tag for Jekyll&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt; over at GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 11, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/11/external-links-in-the-post-title</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Gummesson 2.0</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make the jump and thus this site now has a spanking new design. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Oswald&quot; title=&quot;Oswald&quot;&gt;Oswald&lt;/a&gt; is used for the headings and the navigation and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Asap&quot; title=&quot;Asap&quot;&gt;Asap&lt;/a&gt; is used for the body copy. I quite like them together since the former has a kind of slab-serif quality to it, even though it's actually a sans-serif. The bold and italic versions of Asap aren't perfect, but they look much better than than they did before. I haven't had the chance you check out how they look in &lt;em&gt;Firefox&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Opera&lt;/em&gt;, but I hope they look good in them too. I've also increased the font size from 112.5% &lt;em&gt;(which usually equals to 18px)&lt;/em&gt; to 125% &lt;em&gt;(20px)&lt;/em&gt; just because I'm a big fan of having a bigger size for readability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September 10, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/10/gummesson-two-point-zero</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>Redesigning</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though this site isn't even a month old I'm having serious thoughts about redesigning it. In fact, I already have a design that's about 99% finished. I'm having a hard time deciding if I really should switch or not though. One minute I'm liking the current design (atleast the basic structure of it) and the next I dislike it. One thing I really don't like with it is that the default typeface used for the body copy (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Vollkorn&quot;&gt;Vollkorn&lt;/a&gt;) looks really nice as long as you don't use the bold and italic font styles on your text. The bold looks really heavy compared to the normal weight and that bugs me quite much. The italic version looks okay, but I'm not totally happy with it. The typography is a big part of this site's design (if not the only part) since I'm not a really graphical designer (I wouldn't even call myself a designer, to be honest).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight I probably should've spent more time on choosing the right typefaces earlier, but I was eager to launch this site so I didn't. So, I guess the conclusion of this post is that I'll likely change the typefaces, but stick to the one column layout. I'm thinking about cleaning up the code a bit too, but we'll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September  7, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/07/redesigning</link>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                <title>A Hard (Drive) Failure</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago my new hard drive that I bought a mere three weeks ago decided that it was time to make my life not so fun by giving up. For some reason it failed, and it failed hard. Luckily, I had all of my important files (like this whole site) stored on an external drive and I have a SSD where I can keep my OS and all of my programs and such, but some of my other files are forever lost. It sucks, but I'll survive. My brother (who really helped med out) fought like a champ trying to get it to work, but it was a lost cause. In the process of trying to save my new hard drive I also had to wipe my SSD too. It took quite a while to install everything again, but now it's all up and running. The &quot;failed to sync branch&quot; problem I had earlier with GitHub is also gone, which I guess you could say is good, even though I would've rather had that problem than going trough this whole ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't really know if I'm more sad or more angry though. Sure, it's really important that you take backups of everything that you want to keep and store, but I don't think I really can blame myself entirely in this case. I mean, you don't really except a hard drive that you've barely used to break down and just fail on you so suddenly. On the other hand I do want to kick myself in the head, atleast just a little bit. Oh well. Sometimes we think that computers are these indestructible things that can do no wrong, but I guess that's not really the case. Now I'm keeping my fingers crossed that I can get it replaced without any hassles, but that shouldn't really be a problem. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <published>September  5, 2012</published>
                <link>http://ellengummesson.com/blog/2012/09/05/a-hard-drive-failure</link>
              </item>
            
    </channel>
  </rss>